<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site.
 It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content.
 You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another.
 This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site.

 To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps:
 1. Log in to that site as an administrator.
 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel.
 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list.
 4. Activate & Run Importer.
 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page.
 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users
    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an
    existing user on the site or to create a new user.
 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc.
    contained in this file into your site.
-->
<!-- generator="WordPress.com" created="2021-05-18 13:04"-->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/">
  <channel>
<title>Eunice Park</title>
<link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com</link>
<description>a website </description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 13:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
<language>en</language>
<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
<wp:base_site_url>https://wordpress.com/</wp:base_site_url>
<wp:base_blog_url>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com</wp:base_blog_url>
<wp:author>
  <wp:author_login>homeofwordsblog</wp:author_login>
  <wp:author_email>jyeunicepark@gmail.com</wp:author_email>
  <wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Eunice P.]]></wp:author_display_name>
  <wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name>
  <wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name>
</wp:author>
<wp:category>
  <wp:term_id>178</wp:term_id>
  <wp:category_nicename>books</wp:category_nicename>
  <wp:category_parent/>
  <wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Books]]></wp:cat_name>
</wp:category>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>1359</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>primary</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[Primary]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>1360</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>social</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[Social]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<image>
		<url>https://s0.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Eunice Park</title>
		<link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<item>
  <title>A Billion Dollar Whale (Book Review)</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/04/06/example-post/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 06:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=11</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>"It's tempting to see this kind of corruption as a disease afflicting poor countries, where kleptocrats live in splendor of the expense of their long-suffering populations. But Jho Low's crime is a modern take on that old story."</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"width":248,"height":375} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/51xSjpRxWnL.jpg" alt="Amazon.com: Billion Dollar Whale: The Man Who Fooled Wall Street ..." width="248" height="375" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>An astounding story of how Jho Low, the man behind the infamous 1MDB fraud, went on a heist starting with its country, then Middle East kingdom, to Wall Street, Hollywood and beyond. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The story of Jho Low is a recurring theme of how profits can help turn blind eyes to injustice and inequality. His story also serves as a dire warning of what may be ahead of us if profitability is everything. After reading this book, I have helped myself supplement with visual aids by watching Dirty Money episode two, which deals exactly on the corruption of Malaysia and its government. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Jho Low and his allies pursue unprecedented pleasures and luxuries at the expense of their helpless citizens. Tom Wright and Bradley Hope who authored this book not only offers a detailed narrative of how 1MDB came to be, but also pose a grave warning to those in power or those who aspire to be in power, how frail a kingdom stands when it is built on debauchery, theft, and greed. Billion Dollar Whale is an expose of a crime that is widely practiced over the world albeit its scale smaller or executed into a furtive method (it is unbelievable how big names in Wallstreet, celebrities, political powers can fool themselves into this plain fraud): how investment banks take advantage of the lose compliance and regulations in emerging markets by taking part in sovereign wealth funds / how supermodels  who live comfortable by Central Park/Beverly Hills still would display cloying behaviors to a fat Chinese boy for $$ / how countless people still depend on connections and its leverage to take a short-cut to the success or elite circle. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While reading, readers can get lost in the elaborate description of how Jho Low manoeuvred money laundrying through labyrinth-like manipulation of shell companies, but this book does not fail to unearth every little dirty secret with no leaves unturned; undoubtedly offers a lesson in short: nobody is over the law.  Not even the smartest in the room. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>11</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-04-06 06:27:50</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-04-06 06:27:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>example-post</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>sharing_disabled</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>switch_like_status</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:0;N;}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_starter_page_template</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[42684107782]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Philosopher (Review)</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/04/07/new-philosopher-review/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 06:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=81</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whenever I have the chance at the airports, I never fail to stop by their bookstores. Many newly published books that are not available in local bookstores can be easily spotted in the international airports (and in English). And it is also very interesting to see what the other transitors buy to read when they have too much time to kill (layovers, delays, just early comers like me). </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":83,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/screenshot-2020-04-07-at-1.01.26-pm.png?w=396" alt="" class="wp-image-83" /></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I was lucky last year to have stumbled across an edition of New Philosopher - BEING HUMAN: ALL ABOUT US in Melbourne. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>My association with magazines so far shamefully was with celebrity gossips, next hot things to shop for Christmas, interiors, destinations, or aesthetics. From Vogue to Kinfolk to Magazine B and the likes. Well, never have I ever imagined that there could be a magazine on philosophy, but it was a pleasant surprise and this is probably the most re-read publications I have at home. (It is also ad-free!)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Creators of New Philosopher, the quarterly publication, are also behind Womankind, a women's magazine that I have yet to delve into. Its work is poetic yet intellectual, addressing the most imminent or trending human dilemma in this century. The graphics that punctuate large the pages often act as important as the bodies of words. The delivery of message is simply phenomenal. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:coblocks/gallery-masonry -->
<div class="wp-block-coblocks-gallery-masonry"><div class="coblocks-gallery has-no-alignment has-caption-style-dark has-gutter"><ul class="has-grid-xlrg has-gutter-15 has-gutter-mobile-15"><li class="coblocks-gallery--item"><figure class="coblocks-gallery--figure"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/screenshot-2020-04-07-at-1.16.29-pm-2.png?w=369" alt="" data-id="91" data-imglink="" data-link="https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/screenshot-2020-04-07-at-1-16-29-pm-2/" class="wp-image-91" /></figure></li><li class="coblocks-gallery--item"><figure class="coblocks-gallery--figure"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/screenshot-2020-04-07-at-1.16.21-pm-2.png?w=376" alt="" data-id="90" data-imglink="" data-link="https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/screenshot-2020-04-07-at-1-16-21-pm-2/" class="wp-image-90" /></figure></li><li class="coblocks-gallery--item"><figure class="coblocks-gallery--figure"><img data-imglink="" /></figure></li><li class="coblocks-gallery--item"><figure class="coblocks-gallery--figure"><img data-imglink="" /></figure></li></ul></div></div>
<!-- /wp:coblocks/gallery-masonry -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I used to be a devoted reader of Reader's Digest during my youthful(?) years because it gave me the warm consolation I needed as angsty teen, reading tacit feelings/thoughts that I was not able to express literalized  by someone else (the exact same comfort of reading Chicken's Soup for the Soul). New Philosopher does this in a more refined and elevated way. It brings novel ideas and new school of thoughts, making reading, pausing, and thinking in between the lines and pages absolutely necessary. This is probably what <a href="http://www.theschooloflife.com">School Of </a><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.theschooloflife.com" target="_blank">Life</a> would look like if it had a (ma')cousin. Sorry for the trashy pun.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":94,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/ayeur-aul-account-copy.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-94" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":95,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/reviled-copy.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-95" /><figcaption>more books to add on TBR!</figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is not your average coffee table magazine, which with time gets outdated, barely flipped through, or just there for the aesthetics. Once a visitor did ask me if I put this publication on my shelf for "display" / for the 'gram. Well, yes and no: yes -- it is aesthetically pleasing to own and have, indeed it adds a little vibrancy to my bookshelf filled with stacks of black penguin classics, but no -- beyond my seemingly superficial display of intellectual and philosophical curiosity, I do read it, and many times over, and it repeatedly puts me into thought.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":92,"width":385,"height":330,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/screenshot-2020-04-07-at-1.16.36-pm-1.png?w=591" alt="" class="wp-image-92" width="385" height="330" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As a big fan of cultural criticism, I can confidently say that New Philosopher does not fail to vividly lay out our current cultural phenomenon and boldly question widely accepted norms. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>130 page in total, it is no quick-easy read. But little did I acknowledged the time passing, completely engrossed between its pages, I almost missed my flight when I arrived at the last page of this edition. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>More Books to Read on Philosophy / Humanity: </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:group -->
<div class="wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container"><!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Sapiens &amp; Homo Deus by Yuval Noah Harari</li><li><a href="http://www.yes24.com/Product/Goods/80499154">Eight by Ji Sung Lee </a>(not sure if they have an English version) </li><li>Sophie's World by Jostein Gaarder</li><li>Thank You For Being Late by Thomas L. Friedman</li><li>The Empathy Instinct by Peter Bazalgette</li><li><a href="https://www.theschooloflife.com/shop/books/">The Meaning of Life by The School of Life</a> </li><li>Man's Search for Meaning by Victor Frankl</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:group -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>81</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-04-07 14:20:08</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-04-07 06:20:08</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>new-philosopher-review</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1586240411]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[42723825965]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Bluest Eyes by Toni Morrison</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/04/12/the-bluest-eyes-by-toni-morrison/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 11:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=110</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Sodden with discrimination, violation and rape, young Pecola finds herself unlovable and eternally deprived of what she cannot have but which seem to make everybody (esp. the adults) adore and love little girls her age --- a pair of blue eyes. Blue eyes signify not only racial superiority but class elitism, the world seen through blue eyes wouldn't have been different at all, but to Pecola it did, it changed everything. How she was treated, who she was associated with, and where she could go. Pecola remained nobody and even outrageously hated on, as long as she kept her ruddy appearance --- dark skin and black eyes. They became the origin of the hatred. To her, she deserved the treatment because of her eyes. To her, blue eyes were a symbol of status and it was something nobody could take away from her, but where could she trade for a pair of blue eyes? </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It does not seem to greatly disturb Pecola even when she was sexually violated by her own father and had yet to go through series of tragedies. Her desire to obtain a pair of blue eyes withstands them all. She remains adamant and obsessive. Everything else doesn't matter.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Toni Morrison concludes the book with a dialogue between Frieda and Claudia (her childhood friends) about seeds that do not grow on some lands. Young, innocent, naive, and pure, yet smart, these girls could have blossomed into graceful, loving women of strength, but the seeds did not grow on the land they were planted. They did not grow as if to say that they did not belong, or maybe they knew, even if they grow into the finest of its own kind, they were to be treaded on by their neighbor, their own parents, and even the holy ordained of God.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It didn't suffice that Pecola finally had a pair of blue eyes ----- she needed the bluest eyes of them all. Throughout the entire story, I could hear that which sat in the deepest corner of her heart: gaping and yawning holes want of attention, beauty, adoration, and love. In another world without ugliness, isolation, and harshness, would Pecola have still prayed for blue eyes? And there as I sat reading, I saw the selfsame holes in mine, wishing I had a pair of blue eyes in my own terms. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>"They had stared at her with great uncomprehending eyes. Eyes that questioned nothing and asked everything. Unblinking and unabashed, they stared up at her. The end of the world lay in their eyes, and the beginning, and all the waste in between."</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[They had stared at her with great uncomprehending eyes. Eyes that questioned nothing and asked everything. Unblinking and unabashed, they stared up at her. The end of the world lay in their eyes, and the beginning, and all the waste in between.]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>110</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-04-12 19:54:51</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-04-12 11:54:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-bluest-eyes-by-toni-morrison</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[42933470886]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1586692494]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The 100-Year Life by Lynda Gratton &amp; Andrew Scott</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/04/15/the-100-year-life-by-lynda-gratton-andrew-scott/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 02:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=139</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Recommended to me by my friend Amanda, this book describes and explains its main thesis: increased longevity. The authors do a great job in roughly painting the story of the elongated lifespan and how it is affecting "modern" behaviors such as multiple educational degrees, delayed marriage, job hoppings, etc. They narrate and describe longevity's impact on cultural, social, governmental, and medical aspect in the generations to come. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":144,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/the-100-year-life.png?w=304" alt="" class="wp-image-144" /></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>However, its emphasis on the need for young people to shift on how they think and manage personal finances dominates the book in general. I resonated with many reviews on Goodreads on the point that the book does explains well to the old generation how there will be a paradigm shift in jobs, family, and finances, whereas for young readers, the authors are merely pointing out the obvious, without really offering a practical solution to tackle the uncertainties. Although it is unfair to demand the authors of solid proposals to the answer "What are we to do then?" as evidently nobody knows for sure what the future holds, it could have provided more realistic approach or a more vivid description of how we are to see life and navigate its pathways. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The book also largely projects a shadow of self-centeredness to me throughout the discussion. With the identity economics in large, with people asking questions on "Who am I?", "What makes me essentially me?", "What is my passion?", so on and so forth, people are fixated on the idea of self-actualization in work and in family. The drastic difference with our parental generation lies right here. They have strived and harvested the fruits of their labor without having the "luxuries" of asking whether the jobs they held were what they were passionate about, or if their partners were the true loves of their lives. Realistically, they had families to tend to, and were involved in communities that were closely knitted. It wasn't much about their identity as much as it was about living the life and moving on. It was more about what they could bring to the table, how they could rear and tend to their households, do honest works and stay content, etc. Although prominent in many countries and cultures in the modern world, this particular characteristics (of self actualization) is quite predominant in the "Western world", specifically in the USA. The authors fail to regard family-centric or community-driven decisions that take up a huge chunk of life in the other parts of the world and dwell on its significance --- how this pattern still largely remains in East Asian countries, how it is shaping the youth of our generation and its necessity, too. The mindset of "giving up" or sacrificial decision for family/traditions over passion is somewhat denounced in the chapter that discusses "Exploration," or even hardly dealt with. In the pursuit of happiness, there is no evident victor in this, and ideally, nobody would have to sacrifice their individual self for the larger good, but in my world, and as a twenty-two year old, I still have concerns on my parents, my family and how my life decisions will impact them. And to me undoubtedly the sense of community, a stable family with solid relationships (although not perfect) are central to factoring a happy (hopefully long) life.  </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Unfortunately for me, the book somewhat comes off to me as repetitive. Echoing what one reviewer (paraphrasing), its idea/thesis could have well been told in just a summary. But my takeaway from this is that after all, although the average lifespan of humans can stretch into 100 and more years, on a personal level, we will never know how much time we've got. With the constant threat such as Covid-19, unstable political and economic climates, nobody is guaranteed a fulfilling 100 years of life. This book serves as a good reminder to shake ourselves a little bit from the slumber, and tell ourselves that there is a possibility that our future selves depend largely on the present selves, and that we should make every bit count, maximizing the value of what we have to hedge on the risks of the future. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more info you can visit their website: <a href="http://www.100yearlife.com/">http://www.100yearlife.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you want to dive deeper and contemplate on the future of humanities (and its relation to technology, finance, etc) with me, I recommend you to read:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Sapiens / Homo Deus by Yuval Noah Harari</li><li>Thank You For Being Late by Thomas L. Friedman</li><li>Future of Capitalism by Paul Collier</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>139</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-04-15 10:59:14</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-04-15 02:59:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-100-year-life-by-lynda-gratton-andrew-scott</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[43039118300]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1586919559]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Moonwalking with Einstein by Joshua Foer</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/04/20/moonwalking-with-einstein-by-joshua-foer/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 06:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=150</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"id":157,"width":370,"height":562,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/moonwalking300dpi_custom-905cc16ee937cc7446caef7cda75cebbd235edd2-s800-c85-1.jpg?w=658" alt="" class="wp-image-157" width="370" height="562" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I was watching an episode of Vox's mini series, Mind Explained when I learned about Yanjaa Wintersoul, a grandmaster of memory. Out of curiosity and impressed at such title, I quickly searched her up on Google to see where she was coming from, and started watching one of her Youtube videos introducing the book that sparked her interest in memory and  brought her on the journey of being a World Memory Champion --- Moonwalking with Einstein by Joshua Foer. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":151,"width":540,"height":304,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d95dOH-7GHM"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/maxresdefault.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-151" width="540" height="304" /></a><figcaption><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d95dOH-7GHM">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d95dOH-7GHM</a></figcaption></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Memory plays a crucial role in our lives. We at times are haunted by the vivid recollection of our traumatic experiences; we sweat profusely at the thought of our minds going blank at important exam seatings; we fear one day, as we age, that we will slowly faze into dementia, forgetting who we are and our loved ones. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The author of the book, Joshua Foer, is an experimental journalist, who unfolds his entire journey from being a journalist for the championship to being crowned a USA Memory Champion aided by Ed Cooke a world champion himself. He goes on in the book dissecting how the mental athletes (MAs) memorize decks of cards in thirty minutes, few hundred digits of number, and random indexes of strangers --- tacling the question: is it inborn talent, or is it technique? He interviews people like EP (who suffered from total memory impairment), Kim Peek, Daniel Temmet (savants), to seek out why some people lose their memory, and why some people remember everything and cannot seem to simply forget. The question on nature vs nurture. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Foer goes far beyond this by questioning the role of memory in our life and society. Where does rote memory now stand in education? Why was memory essential to pre-Gutenburg period, before mass publication was available? How is intelligence measured and how should it be measured? He also expands on his discovery of the tight correlation between creativity and memory, which is counterintuitive, claiming that only with creative associations of disparate images/ideas, can one clearly imprint them in memory, even go further and create something new.  </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I personally loved how he reflected on the role of memory in this modern world, when a plethora of technological aids is available which makes the utility of internal memory obsolete: everything is just a Google away. Even Gordon Bell (founding member of Microsoft strongly propagates this belief  in real life and documents everything. I mean, Everything.) Foer writes:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"It's that it is so hard to find occasion to use them in the real world in which paper, computers, cell phones, and Post-its can handle the task of remembering... So why bother investing in one's memory in an age of externalized memories? The best answer I can give is the one that I received unwittingly from EP, whose memory had been so completely lost that he could not place himself in time or place, or relative to other people. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That is: <strong>How we perceive the world and how we act in it are products of how and what we remember.</strong> We're all just a bundle of habits shaped by our memories. And to the extent that we control our lives, we do so by gradually altering those habits, which is to say the network of our memory. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Our ability to find humor in the world, to make connections between previously unconnected notions, to create new ideas, to share in a common culture: All these essentially human acts depend on memory. Now more than ever, as the role of memory in our culture erodes at a faster pace than ever before, we need to cultivate our ability to remember. Our memories make us who we are. They are the seat of our values and source of our character."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In other chapter of the book, I was enlightened by his exposition of the "Ok Plateau," the bane of excellence as Business Insider puts it. Well-written consistently throughout the whole book, important topics like The Major System, Mind Mapping (Tony Buzan) and many other interesting ideas are not lost in the (equally interesting) trivia and discoveries the author shares with the readers -- I was engaged through and through from cover to cover. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Last but not least, I was pleasantly surprised to find out the familiar-last-name author is the brother of the writer Jonathan Safran Foer (his works include: Here I Am, Extremely Loud &amp; Incredibly Close)!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>MORE of Joshua Foer: </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>His other book and also a project - Atlas Obscura: <a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/">https://www.atlasobscura.com/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>His TED Talk: <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/joshua_foer_feats_of_memory_anyone_can_do?language=en">https://www.ted.com/talks/joshua_foer_feats_of_memory_anyone_can_do?language=en</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Interview with The Daily Beast: <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/joshua-foer-how-i-write">https://www.thedailybeast.com/joshua-foer-how-i-write</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>150</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-04-20 14:15:55</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-04-20 06:15:55</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>moonwalking-with-einstein-by-joshua-foer</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[43244613125]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1587363359]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_a346e9a952b1ecd15285e6191a1f243e</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_3cc3469bb38486778dad52e9b9fcac26</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Meritocracy Trap by Daniel Markovits</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/04/28/the-meritocracy-trap-by-daniel-markovits/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 10:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=201</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":203,"width":205,"height":316,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/71t0saaq-2l.jpg?w=666" alt="" class="wp-image-203" width="205" height="316" /></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Class existed as long as civilization (or even humanity) existed. Caste systems, oligarchy, and aristocracy --- they are all drives behind great divide between the upper class/"elites" and the rest of the population in aspects of family, education, and work. The author Daniel Markovits now adds meritocracy to the list, making a compelling case of how meritocracy has gone awry and in fact, claiming that meritocracy is, indeed, aristocracy in its fundamental nature. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Meritocracy, a term coined by Michael Young in his book The Rise of Meritocracy, sounds harmless and progressive in that it acknowledges "earned" (its Latin word - <em>merit</em>) privileges and rewards. However, mature meritocracy was borne out of dysfunctional capitalism, and became just another variation of a class system that corroborates the Matthew Effect even to this day. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“For unto every one that hath shall be given, and he shall have abundance: but from him that hath not shall be taken away even that which he hath,”</p><cite> Matthew 25:29</cite></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Markovits claims that he himself is a product and a grand beneficiary of the meritocratic system --- Yale Law Professor, educated in London School of Economics, Oxford University and the likes. His quest for justice and equality in the current economic/political/social status has led him to pursue the myth of meritocracy and debunk its widely known claims. He argues how meritocracy, while it seems to portray a fair game with promises of equal opportunities to all, is just another form of aristocracy, only differing in that its valuable asset lies in human capital and skills, not in lands, and how its feedback loop constantly puts elites and their offsprings at an unprecedented advantage over the rest (at the price of self exploitation, having to need to work long hours and prove themselves through labor of their wealth, and also to maintain their status). This does not only leave "the rest" in hopeless despair, but also puts the elites on the verge of breakdown. This class differentiation wittily pinned by Markovits as the "useless" and the "used up."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is what the economists call labor market polarization / skill-biased technogical change:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>"Super skills drive technology development to make it more and more productive, making mid-skilled workers obsolete and put at disadvantage." </p><p>"Meritocratic inequality grows -- and meritocracy builds and then reinforces its trap -- through a series of feedback loops. The most importatnt connects meritocratic inequality's two basic building blocks: the exceptional training the rich children receive in school and the extravagant incomes that elite skills sustain at work."</p><cite> The Meritocracy Trap</cite></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Exclusive admission to the best education, top-paying jobs elicit innovations that favor the rich and smart, but eliminates the roles of the rest. Putting countless jobs at risks while the elites crop the harvest in millions and even billions of dollars, this vicious cycle is part of the consequences we face in this "meritocratic" system. Markovits goes even further to call meritocratic achievement, a sham. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Think: more than half of Ivy League graduates (with proven statistics) now take up jobs in either finance, private law, technology, or management consulting, demanding and generating the need to make their salaries at par with their rare, coveted skills and talents (vice versa). This causes exponential rise in pay, and in return a hectic amount of productivity ensued with the technology supplementing, with less and less need for middle-line workers, and innovations pursued by the "upper hand" creating an environment where their skills are highly sought after and rewarded for -- it is simply snowballing inequality. By now, it is clear who the winner of the game is. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Or is it? Markovits makes a case for how in this game, there is no winner in that the elites in their realm have to exploit themselves and muddle their genuine authenticity to maintain their wealth and status. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:media-text {"mediaId":213,"mediaType":"image","mediaWidth":36} -->
<div class="wp-block-media-text alignwide is-stacked-on-mobile" style="grid-template-columns:36% auto;"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/img_4138.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-213" /></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content"><!-- wp:paragraph {"placeholder":"Content\u2026"} -->
<p>After a vast explanation and statistical evidence on how meritocratic inequality is prevalent, pervasive, and destructive in our very lives, he finally reaches to conclusion: What Should We Do? --- my favorite question of all times, because without it, what <em>is</em> the point?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph --></div></div>
<!-- /wp:media-text -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Although the fact that his conclusions are personal and his right to advance his own cause is undeniable, I couldn't help but feel let down in his plead for "workers of the world" to "unite!" This is a political slogan of communism and socialism, famously penned in Karl Marx's Communist Manifesto. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I agree that one ideology cannot completely and fully fix the problems faced in reality, but we can execute a better system, namely capitalism. Capitalism has its own notoriety ("evil rich") and have bought its way to social justice warriors' hatred. Socialism and communism however is not an better alternative. Ideal in its hypothetical world, this political system asks and demands citizens to strip off their personal rights through government interference (the ruling power has the say of "ought" and "ought not", sounds much like totalitarianism?) Capitalism is not, to say the least, the perfect system, but it is the best working market system. Of course, it has its vice in that the freedom is misused to exploitation and greed encouraged, it recognizes the fundamental right of an individual, freedom. I would have to say that this case is more eloquently argued by Ray Dalio. Dalio chimes in with Markovits on taxing richer people and might agree on one or more proposals that Markovits has made, but former does not deny or negate the natural privileges or earned advantages -- it's a lottery of birth as they say; they had no choice either. A better system does not invalidate the rich, but look after the poor and the needy. We can't have a perfect, sterile economy that reaches to 100% equality in real life, but we do need to acknowledge the inequality, fight for equal opportunities, and <strong><em>voluntarily</em></strong> distribute the wealth granted to us that are considered to be economic surplus. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is not to call out the author as a Marxist (he indeed quoted from The Communist Manifesto), yet to jointly converse and discuss practical actions that need to be addressed to better the state that we are in. This, I believe, cannot be contained in the book due to its significance and length. As I was reading this book, I couldn't help but to think realistically on what can be done and how in spite of which political party I belong to. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Another question here is our motive for the fight for equality. Is the inflamed rage of middle-class indeed fuelled by the discontent and jealousy of extravagant lives the elites live -- an unfulfilled desire turned to anger and hatred? Is there a chance that the economic necessity we claim actually is an economic surplus?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For more on meritocracy, capitalism, and the economy: </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Jacobin Mag's interview with the author:</strong> </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>https://www.jacobinmag.com/2019/09/meritocracy-trap-inequality-human-capital-markovits</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Listen to Ezra Klein show's episode on this very topic: </strong>https://www.vox.com/identities/2019/10/21/20897021/meritocracy-economic-mobility-daniel-markovits</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Ray Dalio's articles:</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/why-how-capitalism-needs-reformed-parts-1-2-ray-dalio/</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Or read The Future of Capitalism: Facing the New Anxieties by Paul Collier</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>201</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-04-28 18:22:37</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-04-28 10:22:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-meritocracy-trap-by-daniel-markovits</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="capitalism"><![CDATA[capitalism]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="economy"><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="meritocracy"><![CDATA[meritocracy]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="politics"><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_69d2860b7b47332989e551f66e4b6ecb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_65c1a7ade20fe886c88384ebc2923dfb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_1563651c3620d85927a1a84edc98ad48</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_7a9615a898e697c0b7810173639565b8</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_e8ff7ab506e091575bf2d2c334d457d2</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_4e5280bddfc7cd0c174433e09bad446c</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_3cc3469bb38486778dad52e9b9fcac26</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_71817c1373333f46a199254008c378fd</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1588069360]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[43577279698]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_7b384badaf05b62a5a85f6b34756022a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_b188bce01cecac8512a8234ad0708aa9</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_ca1bef40aa6a65cbd15a77cbd660282d</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_322a300a791fadef000f8214a2e7b6a7</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_d8e589d0464160ea9e20b3c411904127</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_59d1ef220b8b202a34afc7d5c0203f18</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_60662ea2a3436742ddb48dc3c203939f</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_6e8cb0fe66075843838b1dfbb86a1688</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Age of Surveillance Capitalism by Shoshana Zuboff</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/06/03/the-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-by-shoshana-zuboff/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 22:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=227</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","width":238,"height":366} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img src="http://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/06/b1eac-theageofsurveillancecapitalismcover.jpg" alt="CPDP2019 Opening Night: Book Launch of Shoshana Zuboff's &quot;The Age ..." width="238" height="366" /></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You’ve probably heard enough of these buzzwords: big data, artificial intelligence, machine learning, Internet of things, and autonomous cars. Countries with these under their belts have an auspicious future, a clear advantage over other countries in an economic sense, but what does this all mean to consumers, and how does it affect society and its democracy?&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To read this comprehensively is no small feat. Shoshanna Zuboff, the author, goes on a rather long journey of explaining what Surveillance Capitalism is, who are the key players and drivers, what is being done and how. I always like to carry with me the so-called question tool kit 5W1H (who what when where why and how), but would also like to end the remark with the most important question “So what?” The author lays out clear depiction of her findings and makes the case for the future of humanity in a world where technology is ubiquitous and blindly worshipped upon.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Every century or more specifically each industrial revolution seems to have its own narratives, yet it is not hard to site a repeating pattern. To each cycle exists a plantation ground where raw materials are extracted/mined. There was horse and oil for energy in its primitive cycle, then electricity and machineries for mass production, land for agriculture and real estate. Not too long ago, computers paved way for automation, global trading and networks and finally transitioning into the world of clouds and omni-connectivity, humans being the ground that is being tilled on for production.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":228,"width":440,"height":351,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/surveillance-camera.png?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-228" width="440" height="351" /></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The author points out here that in the age of surveillance capitalism, human experiences become the raw materials, us being the land to mine these data from. Data is the new commodity; human experiences is monetised. It is now a well-known fact that the value of data surpassed that of oil (2017, The Economist). The fight for data is the hot bed of all hegemonies and business corps. Here the author also points out that there are three economic imperatives to surveillance capitalism:&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li><em>Scale</em>: The more data you have, the more synergy and the more competitive you are as a business entity. The bigger the better - namely the economies of scale.</li><li><em>Scope</em>:&nbsp; There needs to be different spectrums to draw from, or as Zuboff likes to call it “variety” of data.</li><li>Then there is, <em>Variance</em>: This is where the surveillance capitalist interference of behaviours or human experiences (data) come into play. The surveillance capitalism does not rest satisfied in the fact that they could, with scale and scope of data, predict behaviours (betting on futures — a largely attractive investment), but also aims to manipulate them through intervention.&nbsp;</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We, unconsciously as users of technology, are coaxed into behaviours that would reap the surveillance capitalism big profits (online target ads was its pioneer). It is unsurprising that more than 80% of Google’s revenue stems from advertising. Not only so, we experience meddled governance, Brexit and 2017 US election might be the largest spokesperson of this mechanism. What else can there be?&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","width":559,"height":382} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img src="https://a.scpr.org/i/0d95408fcf3549e3de6793a9206f17a2/201992-full.jpg" alt="The Frame® | Chilling Fallout From 'The Great Hack' | 89.3 KPCC" width="559" height="382" /><figcaption>Source: KPCC</figcaption></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Well, a lot.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The goal for Google “to make information available”, is not a visionary motto, but a strong declaration to claim ownership of the data (our preferences, history, connections, emotions, health, home) to euphemistically “empower us to make the right decisions and make our lives convenient” at the expense of our privacy and individual thoughts.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Democracy is threatened in the name of neoliberalism. Regulations are impediments to growth, and the policies cannot simply catch up with the speed of technological developments. And slowly we fall prey to the giant duopoly (Google and Facebook) for their utopian world (very much like the world that the famed behaviorist B. F. Skinner wrote in his novel Walden II). Unlike the Orwellian dystopia, the engineers of the soul “do not use force [but use] behavioural engineering.” If we follow the logic of the author’s expansive argument, not only do we lose the “right of shelter,” but also “the right to the future tense” to the hands of these Malevolent Gods, or The Big Other, a “world spanning organism.”&nbsp; Indeed Wagner and Heather writes on the importance of self-awareness in self-determination intellectually, psychologically, and physically. &nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Every threat to human autonomy begins with an assault on awareness.”&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":236,"width":350,"height":233,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/5109080982_1fb9a9a14a_b-1.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-236" width="350" height="233" /></figure></div>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And now to the important question: So what?&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So what can we do, but to accept it as humanity’s fate? Is capitalism the foe and communism ever the antidote to our society? My questions on this topic do not end without addressing the psychological distress and social schism (its ever polarising ends) technological advancement has caused. Thomas Friedman writes in his book Thank You For Being Late, “The antidote to being overwhelmed by change is human cooperation and interaction geared toward the common good.” And so the trend says it all — young people are flocking back to farms, nature, (hotels offering ultra luxury, exclusive retreat for the elites), well-being, athleisure, mental health, ESG all is an evidence of humanistic effort to cope with the modern stress we face. The author, as a law professor of Harvard emerita, offers her part from where she stands, to introduce regulations and policies to protect consumers from being indiscriminately mined, unknowingly intervened, and perpetually being followed and watched. Although she does not offer a practical details of how, she does hope that this book serves as a declaration (as Searle puts it). Hoping to lead the frontier in the fight to fundamental rights that humanity deserves. (Economic and social reformations are not quite answered, but are pending. Reading from other great minds such as Paul Collier’s Future of Capitalism is a great supplement to quench our curiosity and make sense of the topic in a broader spectrum.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Future Development</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While reading this book, I was most intrigued by author’s observation and analysis in the two surveillance societies in US and China — the former utilising data as a way to generate profit, the latter to control the mass under authoritarian ruling. This is definitely an interesting contrast in its economic and political sense. They are not that all different in the social sense: ubiquitous surveillance. However, a deeper undertaking of development of AI in China, social credit system, its effect in consumer behaviours and the different landscape of sentiment towards technology from that of the Western world would be topics worth investigating.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":233,"width":408,"height":334,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/google-street-view-2.jpg?w=462" alt="" class="wp-image-233" width="408" height="334" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:image {"id":234,"width":555,"height":333,"sizeSlug":"large"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/20764310-0-image-a-71_1573222627488-2.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-234" width="555" height="333" /></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">MORE:</span></strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>Read</em>: </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>https://www.economist.com/leaders/2017/05/06/the-worlds-most-valuable-resource-is-no-longer-oil-but-data</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://cryptome.org/2015/07/big-other.pdf">https://cryptome.org/2015/07/big-other.pdf</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thank You For Being Late by Thomas Friedman</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>Watch</em>:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Great Hack (Netflix documentary)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>227</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-06-03 06:43:56</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-06-02 22:43:56</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-by-shoshana-zuboff</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_old_date</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020-05-22]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_13cfa55118eb0bee9a692351ee564ab5</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_27b97c6674c1d5bc5614463977a7817b</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_69d2860b7b47332989e551f66e4b6ecb</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_405f6e70bbb4b0321ba2e9d12756cdce</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[45046287888]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1591226139]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_b8271a974017325c2779e8e05d307501</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_08dceb96a3fd7edb4b4d0cda825eb87a</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_b14921c4df8ddb7fb1bd6aa1f4761c91</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_c7bccb13af2ead2b6982fbf83123a600</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The+Age+of+Surveillance+Capitalism+cover</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/06/03/the-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-by-shoshana-zuboff/theageofsurveillancecapitalismcover/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 22:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/06/b1eac-theageofsurveillancecapitalismcover.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>242</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-06-03 06:43:59</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-06-02 22:43:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>theageofsurveillancecapitalismcover</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>227</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/06/b1eac-theageofsurveillancecapitalismcover.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_media_download_success</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1591137839]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_original_import_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/581c722cbebafb2985081b47/1548165707233-YTV7YHOFY0VMJUQRTQEI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNzNPSqfBuIQbC5jpdDUCiF7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UTP6F_yGFDZA5gAA5fPPWRMx0aTC1tjAw603RJUklFgJj98zSYky2TCTwUpJT7udpA/The+Age+of+Surveillance+Capitalism+cover.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>pre_import_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/581c722cbebafb2985081b47/1548165707233-YTV7YHOFY0VMJUQRTQEI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNzNPSqfBuIQbC5jpdDUCiF7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UTP6F_yGFDZA5gAA5fPPWRMx0aTC1tjAw603RJUklFgJj98zSYky2TCTwUpJT7udpA/The+Age+of+Surveillance+Capitalism+cover.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>import_url_remap</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:365:"https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/581c722cbebafb2985081b47/1548165707233-YTV7YHOFY0VMJUQRTQEI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNzNPSqfBuIQbC5jpdDUCiF7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UTP6F_yGFDZA5gAA5fPPWRMx0aTC1tjAw603RJUklFgJj98zSYky2TCTwUpJT7udpA/The+Age+of+Surveillance+Capitalism+cover.jpg";s:97:"http://alwayscarryabo0k.files.wordpress.com/2020/06/b1eac-theageofsurveillancecapitalismcover.jpg";}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>auto_import</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/581c722cbebafb2985081b47/1548165707233-YTV7YHOFY0VMJUQRTQEI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNzNPSqfBuIQbC5jpdDUCiF7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UTP6F_yGFDZA5gAA5fPPWRMx0aTC1tjAw603RJUklFgJj98zSYky2TCTwUpJT7udpA/The+Age+of+Surveillance+Capitalism+cover.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Future of Capitalism: Facing the New Anxieties</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/08/07/the-future-of-capitalism-facing-the-new-anxieties/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 03:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=308</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I have read this book written by Paul Collier earlier this year and was fascinated by his ability to aptly put our modern issues into frame and offer insightful solutions from a global to personal level. This book is on how capitalism has done good, but have gone awry, and how it can be reformed to restore the damage caused.  </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Collier engages the reader with the idea of social/ethical reform of capitalism. It casts out the idea of socialism being an antidote to the failing capitalistic system by echoing Crosby’s pragmatist point of view – “policy was to be judged by whether it worked, not by whether it conformed to the tenets of an ideology." Further galvanizing his ideas that "capitalism needs to be managed, not defeated" with the following rationale. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He claims that the rocks on which we build a strong and better foundation in this capitalism system should be <strong>relationships</strong>. There are three main arenas where relationships are built according to the author: state, firm, and family. He proposes the idea of ethical capitalism (restoring ethics in these three arenas) in the age of universal divide in class, race, and culture. Although he admits that there is no one single ideology that can lift us up from all the despair we are facing in humanity, he firmly believes that 1) capitalism is not equivalent to the depiction of greedy and selfish “economic man” but instead it is what drove global poverty to plummet at an unprecedented rate; 2) neither is socialism nor social paternalism (“believing that state knows the best”) pragmatic; its consequences are by far more destructive and corrupted than capitalism; 3) the current capitalist system we have is not perfect and we can do better.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But how do you define better?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The author defines “better” capitalism as ethical capitalism, a system that “meets standards that are built on our values, honed by practical reasoning, and reproduced by the society itself.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The author puts it clearly and boldly:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“We now have a coherent picture that shows us how individual behavior is shaped by obligations, why it matters, why it might go wrong, and how it might be put right. A society that succeeds in generating many obligations can be more generous and harmonious than one relying only on rights. Obligations are to rights what taxation is to public spending.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We often neglect the responsibility that entails the freedom and autonomy we are granted, but instead crave for more endowments/privileges and rely on governmental intervention to fulfill social justice in this era. For many decades, neglect has led to social discordance and have mutated capitalism into polarized, shameful and fearful system that tears our society apart, putting us into deeper anxiety and despair. To restore capitalism, it is vital to restore sense of reciprocity and relationships that lie within the previously mentioned areas: state, firm, and family.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"style":{"typography":{"fontSize":22}}} -->
<p style="font-size:22px;"><em>STATE</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When performing generosity and good deeds is relied on legal interventions, the behaviors that we will see in society would be opportunistic. This will only induce increasing distrust and resentment in the society. Indeed, we can already see this trend taking gradual effect. After he writes on what the state should not do, he goes on to write how political leaders have a huge responsibility in delivering a narrative that offers a message that is inclusive of the diverse population within a shared place. Dispelling the nationalistic and populist notion, he emphasizes that it is beneficial for a nation to have a shared interest and create reciprocal obligation to those who are within the space at the least. The author points out an important aspect in how a stronger sense of national identity and being patriotic (without being a nationalist) can reinforce a better society in this sense. He offers a viable concept of nationality into “binding people together with a sense of belonging to the same place.” </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>No doubt, there is a lot of work to be done in the realm of politics.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"style":{"typography":{"fontSize":22}}} -->
<p style="font-size:22px;"><em>FIRM</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Firms are at the core of capitalism.” Infamous for its Milton Freedman’s approach, corporates are often depicted as the ruthless and corrupted mercenary; heartless head unit of our society. Recently it has evolved to a strikingly different landscape. From where profitability was all that mattered, to now where value delivery to stakeholders is the center of attention among the corporates, ESG (Environmental, Social &amp; Governmental) are the driving factors of a business success. This is primarily driven by the revelation that a company’s business sustainability has to be envisioned in the stretch of a long-term strategy, rather than short-term results (quarterly earnings).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Firms need a purpose that drives social change (more than just a PR). Here, policies can also play a role in transforming and enhancing the narratives that firms are beneficial to the society. There are many ways a firm can execute this. Consequently, people that make up the workforce of such companies will partake in this bigger initiative as an ethical citizen, promoting a larger social good than mere self-interest. We will then be a step closer to knitting the community through mutual obligations and trust.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"style":{"typography":{"fontSize":22}}} -->
<p style="font-size:22px;"><em>FAMILY</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Ethical obligation is by far most evident in the basic unit of social network -- family. Husband and wife, parents to children, then children to parents, etc. &nbsp;Unsurprisingly in this modern world, self interest overrides benefit of the group. Self-fulfillment and personal achievement trumps well-being of the family and are often hailed as the essence of what constitutes a happy life. I recall the remark made by famed relationship psychologist Esther Perel who puts it this way: “We used to divorce because we were unhappy. Now we divorce to become happier.” Shockingly high rate of divorce, single parenthood, segregation and disintegration of the young and old all contribute negatively to the disparity in wealth distribution and class mobility. (Author references to a book written by Gregory Clark’s <em>The Son Also Rises</em>, which studies the hereditary character of wealth that passes on to many generations.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>“Finding ourselves through losing ourselves.”</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The denial of responsibility for family, as Collier terms it, is “less of a moral awakening than the easy pleasure of moral posturing.” He supports his statement with authors such as David Brooks and Dietrich Bonhoeffer, who all champions obligation performed as the key to restoring fulfillment. We cannot fulfill self-actualization by narrowing our focus to self. It is in the servitude of others that we find meaning and well-being in life. Collier cleverly concludes, “The replacement of the ethical family by the entitled individual is revealed to be more tragedy than triumph.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:separator -->
<hr class="wp-block-separator" />
<!-- /wp:separator -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In Part Two of the book, the author discusses the practicality of deploying his ideas and suggestions in areas such as refuges, HIV, inclusiveness in a global world, taxation (Henry George’s Theorem), education, and so on.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Here are few key insights and quotes (among many) that I would like to highlight before concluding this review.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>On Identity Economics</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Collier also pulls up one insight in the destructiveness and decline of our ethical social democracy in the current age: identity economics. He argues that our identity is a source of self-esteem and we choose where we stem our identity in – it can be work, nation, or any other membership-group. One of the reasons, some social elites denigrate their own nations is because their countries fail to provide the self-esteem they are seeking for. They drop this source (their own country in this case) to signal their identity and moral superiority (<em>Michael Spence’s Theory of Signalling</em>). He points out how the society encourages people to identify victim-hood as a characteristic of identity and embrace it as their source of esteem.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>On Work</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Talented young people need to be brought face-to-face with the social implications of their career choices: how are mega-incomes actually being generated?”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Many people find themselves in jobs that offer too little opportunity for self-respect: they contain insufficient skill for it to be a source of price, or they lack the satisfaction that comes from knowing that what you do contributes to society. This, rather than simply the differences in pay packets, is the crux of the failures by which divergences between families become divergences between jobs. The income inequalities matter and get larger as life progresses through to retirement. But if they are only addressed by redistribution, not only will the required taxation-cum-benefits be enormous, the core deficiency of purpose, or meaning, will be accentuated. Many people will be living on the productivity of others.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The challenge is to reduce the widening dispersion of productivities. Addressing it has taken us through a long march that began with the switch from <strong>social paternalism</strong>, in which the state polices recalcitrant families, to <strong>social maternalism</strong>, in which the sate cushions them with practical support.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"fontSize":"small"} -->
<p class="has-small-font-size">Disclaimer: While writing this review, I have tried my best to be as least reductionist as possible but at the same time, avoid the temptation to copy verbatim from the book while covering all important points in the book.  Paul Collier's ideas are not only extensive and insightful, but his arguments are also well-supported with intellectual clarity and historical precedents. My review does little justice, if not unintended distortions to his points. I highly recommend you to pick up this book and read it for yourself. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>308</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-08-07 11:37:44</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-08-07 03:37:44</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-future-of-capitalism-facing-the-new-anxieties</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[47437837623]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[311]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1596771468]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>future of capitalism</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/08/07/the-future-of-capitalism-facing-the-new-anxieties/future-of-capitalism/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 03:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/future-of-capitalism.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>311</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-08-07 11:31:51</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-08-07 03:31:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>future-of-capitalism</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>308</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/future-of-capitalism.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How To Be Alone by Jonathan Franzen (Essay Collections)</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/08/30/how-to-be-alone-by-jonathan-franzen-essay-collections/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 07:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=324</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Jonathan Franzen is known for being a novelist, but also as an essayist for writing his outspoken thoughts on culture, community, and self reflection/speculation (let's say dignity). I've read his other work, The End of the End of the Earth prior to this, and I can say I will never get enough of his illustrative storytelling skills and his great insights that draw upon these accounts.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The book is not a guide on how to be alone, but more of author's recount on his attempt at being alone. In one of my favorite chapters, Franzen sold his TV away to rid of distraction and sustain solidarity, and he records, "I mourn the eclipse of the cultural authority that literature once possessed, and I rue the onset of an age so anxious that the pleasure of a text becomes difficult to sustain. I don't suppose that many other people will give away their TVs. I'm not sure I'll last long myself without buying a new one. But the first lesson reading teaches is how to be alone."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Another chapter of this book (titled: My Father's Brain) which touches on his father's Alzheimer's disease was thoroughly enjoyable, moving and equally thought-provoking. Franzen mourns on the cruel environments that dementia can put victims through and likens dementia to death in slow motion: you first lose autonomy, you lose memory, then self consciousness, personality, finally the body. His statement on how words particularly console him through this tough time, that stories and permanent words outlast our finite lives, really made me realize how dependent the author was on words, letters, and books. In another book, he echoes, "Books saved me." He also believes that "fiction ... was the transmutation of experiential dross into linguistic gold. Fiction meant taking up whatever the world had abandoned by the road and making beautiful out of it."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He says, "The will to record indelibly, to set down stories in permanent words, seems to me akin to the conviction that we are larger than our biologies. I wonder if our current cultural susceptibility to the charms of materialism - our increasing willingness to see psychology as chemical, identity as genetic, and behavior as the product of bygone exigencies of human evolution - isn't intimately related to the postmodern resurgence of the oral and the eclipse of the written: our incessant telephoning, our ephemeral e-mailing, our steadfast devotion to the flickering tube."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I appreciate Franzen's frank opinion on advanced technology and how it brought about the demise of thoughtful readers and our ability to stay in the present (moreover, alone). He takes shelter in books (esp. fictions) and refuge in being present, "I knew I was happy then, and so I can look back on those years and not miss them. I was present when they happened, and that's enough." I don't think I have had many moments in life where I can confidently say the same.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I'm not wielding literary superiority over people who don't read or watch TVs, but I have to say our generation needs to learn how to sit and read without distraction. I'm guilty as heck of spending too much time on social media, but at least for the duration of this book, I was alone, reading. And reading books is how I will be coping my gravitating need to be online.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Franzen made me think and he made me want to read.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now if you will, please leave me alone.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>324</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-08-30 15:24:03</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-08-30 07:24:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>how-to-be-alone-by-jonathan-franzen-essay-collections</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1598772247]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[48273254847]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[328]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>81bqzpP7IvL</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/08/30/how-to-be-alone-by-jonathan-franzen-essay-collections/81bqzpp7ivl/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 07:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/81bqzpp7ivl.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>328</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-08-30 15:21:40</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-08-30 07:21:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>81bqzpp7ivl</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>324</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/81bqzpp7ivl.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Retreat of Western Liberalism by Edward Luce</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/10/19/the-retreat-of-western-liberalism-by-edward-luce/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 08:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=333</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Edward Luce, the author of the book, discusses globalisation that has been taking place post 1997 and details its impact on economy, politics, social identity and technology, particularly in the West. He offers insightful telling of the history and the consequences economic development has brought about in the modern times ----- how despite material affluence and advanced technology, we are still faced by ever divisive political parties, increasing geopolitical tension and rise of populism/nationalism.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He begins with the convergence of the international countries in the early days post-WW2. How Washington Consensus has offered economic support to countries willing to espouse the idea of democracy as a precondition to its monetary fundings. However, both in 1994 for Mexico and 1997 for South Korea, financial crisis loomed over the countries and have tainted democracy's full guarantee of economic growth. On the other hand, the recent Beijing Consensus generously provided loans to countries in South Africa, South America, and many more in South East Asia "without strings attached" unlike the 'missionary zealots' from the US. Democracy was no longer the absolute holder of truth or virtue. Political divergence has started to take place. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Despair experienced by the younger generation who had high hopes that democracy (or more specifically, meritocracy) will lift them out of poverty and stratified social class, started to lose hope for the future due to the widening gaps of inequality. The growing GDP and comparatively low inflation rate were no longer relevant indicators that reflected the actual growth, as material products were cheap, but the cost for services such as healthcare and college education sky-rocketed. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><br>"Inflation rate does not capture what most people value. Without good health and a good job in tomorrow’s economy, your life’s chances are badly handicapped. This is not an outgrowth of people’s frustrated imaginations."</p></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Luce quoted on Robert Frank to illustrate the illusion of meritocracy,  “If you want to be smart and highly energetic, the most important single step you could take is to choose the right parents.” This is dealt more in depth by the book, The Meritocracy Trap by Markovitz (which I have already written a review on). Although 'meritocracy' carries a different implication these days, initially, Michael Young, the author of The Rise of the Meritocracy and the very person who coined the term 'meritocracy', wrote the book as a satire on the imagined ruling classes of the future. How this is quickly becoming true! Meritocracy is no longer a pathway to fulfilling the "American Dream" but a mere format change in aristocracy. Young predicts that his meritocratic society would come crumbling down "under the weight of its own contradictions by 2033".</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Another one of the great casualties of this global sense of listlessness has been the steep rise in suicides (opioid crisis) and the ever declining willingness to invest in the present (soaring higher education costs). Intolerance of different point of view and virtue signalling, SJWs and heroism puts everybody under surveillance, calling for a war from within as if external threats and competitions were not enough. When Adam Smith wrote The Wealth Of Nations, the book was also followed by the The Theory of Moral Sentiments, but many people seem to be ignorant of the fact. Smith states that when social trust falls, the cost of doing business rises. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In short: from the rise of inequality to populism, Luce argues for a better way to measure growth, progress, and development, poses the irony of rising economy but shrinking politics (nations facing tri-lemma, making it impossible to pursue democracy, national determination and economic globalisation simultaneously), and questions the vindication of meritocratic system for the middle class and their American dream. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Luce further argues that turning back against the Labour Party, blue collars, or the so-called Silent Majority is to blame for the current seated powers in Europe and United States. Overflowing with elites, the political left has simply left out the "void" and failed to represent the middle class of the population. Detachment of theoretical policies and social insecurities faced by the blue collars is the verdict of rising populism and nationalism. Erosion of health care, pension, social securities puts people's concern directly against immigration policies. As Francis Fukuyama says, "Something has to give." There can't be increased NHS, and social welfare, when there are increasing number of immigrants who can rightfully claim the pie as equals. Evidently from the election of Trump (not to mention Brexit, Le Pen's popular support and Brazil's election), democracy starts waning as society turns its back on the 21st century minorities, which counterintuitively, are the “awakened whites” in the case of USA. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“The story of liberal democracy is thus continual tension between the neat democratic folk theory and the more complex liberal idea.”</p></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The marginalised populations are not ignorant, they are indignant because they believe they were deceived by the politicians. This is where the crisis of liberal democracy lies. Distant memories of war and fascism for the younger generation explains the dwindling support for democracy. Social tides are against these "awakened whites", gentrification of race and status are blowing off the social trust and contract United States was founded upon, blaming the demise of democracy on this Silent Majority. However, Mark Lilla, a professor of humanities at Columbia University, has called for an end to identity politics, attributing fascism as identity play based off of group rights, whereas liberalism should find its basis on the individual rights.  </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Wars were unthinkable in the age of internet, within and without. But it looks like we are already in the midst, or we are at the brink of the next great world war. Are we ever safe from wars? </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong><em>“Do we ever learn from history? If so, the parallels between the world today and the world in 1914 should strike us forcefully. Then, as now; the world’s big economies were deeply intertwined. The decades preceding the First World War marked a peak of globalisation that the world economy only regained in the 1990s. Like today, people believed ever-deepening ties of commerce renewed the idea of war irrational. It was thus unthinkable. People had grown complacent after decades of peace. Of course, there was always the crackle of distant gunfire, such as Britain’s Boer War, in South Africa, and periodic colonial skirmishes on almost every continent. But the last real clash between the ’civilised powers’ had been ore than forty years before, in the 1970-1 Franco-German War. Even the, it was strictly lateral. Europe’s last big war wrapped up almost a century before, with Napoleon’s defeat at Waterloo. Much like my own germination, someone of Keynes’s age was unlikely to have direct experience of conflict - or any real fears they would be touted directly by war. Like the Boer War, the invasion of Iraq in 2003 took place in another time zone and was fought by primarily lower-class volunteer army. The rest of us carried on shopping, as George W. Bush had urged us to do. More to the point, there was plenty of appetite to shop. Just as we exult in our Apple products and artisanal coffee, so Keynes’s generation revelled in their Darjeeling tea and the internal combustion engine.” </em></strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This paragraph perfectly sums up our current phenomena, where democracy is at stake, not only due to the rise of China and its threatening power to replace US as a global leader, but also because of the war within itself. The great divide of left and right within US is posing as a greater threat to liberal democracy more than it seems. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Luce writes, with significant clarity and wisdom, the world we are in. He doesn’t offer practical how-to’s to counter the coming demise of liberal democracy, but provides this book as a statement and a declaration — much like Collier’s Future of Capitalism and Zuboff’s book on technology and surveillance capitalism. It is a book to warn us the consequences when we forget history. He gravely warns the readers of ignorance, calling for eternal vigilance to sustain liberty.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One of the most memorable section while reading was the manipulation of the power in constructing illiberal democracy -- this is indeed scarier than autocracy which is easy to spot. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The author writes, "Orwell’s fear was that Big Brother would always be watching you. Huxley's dread was that we would be too busy watching Big Brother on TV to care. There is no need to ban books if people are not reading them. If the people are entertained, they will also be docile."</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p> As mentioned previously regarding the social divide between political left and right, ubiquitous cancel culture, rising intolerance, active witch hunting by small brothers and sisters (in contrast to Big Brother), social media heroism and virtue signalling... These all are just a fraction of what creates a false sense of moral superiority and freedom. An illusion of democracy; an illiberal democracy. Truth is the only casualty of this ongoing war. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"fontSize":"small"} -->
<p class="has-small-font-size"><em>The author does spend quite a large portion in the book discussing potential escalation of tension between China and US (The Thucidydes' Trap) and rise of the East, and what it can mean to the changing world order, but it has been left out in my review as this subject has been covered in great depth by Elizabeth Economy in her book, The Third Revolution, which I have finished reading recently and am planning to write a book review on soon. Stay tuned!</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>333</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-10-19 16:06:34</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-10-19 08:06:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-retreat-of-western-liberalism-by-edward-luce</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[334]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50088493737]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1603094796]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Coddling of the American Mind</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/10/28/the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/?p=351</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Coddling of the American Mind - <em>How Good Intentions and Bad Ideas Are Setting Up a Generation for Failure </em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Summary: The authors address the idea of freedom of speech that has stirred up recent disruptive campus events and delve into what is causing the monumental shift in political polarization. They draw from great insights and their own experiences on how to combat what is at the threat of a decent conversation (at least) and on a higher level, democracy and human flourishing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Three main bad ideas are discussed in the beginning: </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li>Fragility</li><li>Emotional reasoning</li><li>Dualistic thinking</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Fragility</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>"Safetyism deprives young people of the experiences that their antifragile minds need, thereby making them more fragile, anxious, and prone to seeing themselves as victims."</p></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Modern issues prominently found in iGen (those who are born after 1995/6; a term used by Jean Twenge in her book) are notably depression, anxiety, and many other anti-social behaviors. Lukianoff and Haidt finds culprit in the cultivation of safetyism, from family to campus and even to workplace. In the name of equality, inclusion, and social justice, opinions and speech have been censored and heavily regulated. Rather than inviting the students to participate in discussion with people with opposing views, campuses offered a "safe space" for them to "feel safe," instilling the idea that being exposed to such views would aggravate their psychological well-being. At first glance, this seems to be bolstering and championing students' mental health but instead, it is backfiring in a way where these type of "helicopter parenting" and over-protectionism is actually failing to prepare students for the reality. Making them more fragile and making them into thinking they are fragile, students graduate from college unprepared for the "harsh" world to come. The authors in no way condones hate speech or violent ideologies, but instead strongly stands against such. However, the safety-ism approach that the administrators of the universities have been taking more recently seems to be propagating a certain set of belief, as opposed to enabling a platform of diverse opinions. In defense of diversity, educational institutions have significantly improved equal access to opportunities for the racial/ethnic and gender minorities, but have failed to done so for diversity in opinions and ideas. Students are showing symptoms of fragility when studies prove that humans, especially kids and teens are in fact antifragile (Nassim Taleb's Antifragile). Concept creeping such as 'PTSD' or 'safety' increases oversensitivity and incite overprotection. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Emotional Reasoning </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Feeling based objectivism: Letting your feelings determine the truth. This can be a dangerous pitfall in justifying and objectifying cognitive distortions. Cognitive distortions can come in many forms. Below are the few list provided by the authors (expansive list can be found in <em>Treatment Plans and Interventions for Depression and Anxiety Disorders</em>): </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Emotional reasoning</li><li>Catastrophizing</li><li>Overgeneralizing</li><li>Dichotomous thinking</li><li>Mind reading</li><li>Labeling</li><li>Negative filtering</li><li>Discounting positives</li><li>Blaming</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Developing schemas around these bases are fundamentally harmful in building up critical thinking and nurturing resilient mindset. Acknowledging the fact that we all fall prey into cognitive distortions from time to time keep us from projecting ourselves as victims or helpless beings. Lukianoff, one of the authors, testify that he was able to overcome severe depression through cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) and suggests readers to exercise CBT to overcome cognitive dissonance (and of course seek for professional help when necessary). Instilling thoughts that opinions and words are to be measured up against impact (over intention) such as "Your thoughts make me feel unsafe" foster an environment that solicits interpretation of all 'uncomfortable' ideas into an act of 'micro-aggression.' </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Dualistic or binary thinking</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>"Call-out cultures and us-versus-them thinking are incompatible with the educational and research missions of universities, which require free inquiry, dissent, evidence-based argument, and intellectual honesty."</p></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Black and white world view is especially evident in the political world, where the other side is demonized, dehumanized, and labeled as complete evil. The understanding that there needs to be a spectrum enables decent, civilized two-way communication. However it seems that the world now is enjoying quite a ride in witch-hunting and condemning (demonstrating and exercising call-out and cancel culture --- aka public media "lynching") ideas that may differ. One act of offence demands cancellation of the person in his/her total being and deserves merciless boycott/unfollow/cancellation. This binary thought paradigm evokes and shapes up schemas that permeates through every corner of the society where: black vs white; female vs male; us vs them; good vs evil; victim vs oppressor. The rise and play of identity politics are severe issues that stem from this very dualistic approach in processing today's problems. It is also very important that we as humans, commit to erroneous thoughts and ideas, and humans collectively have to be ready to forgive and be more generous about the mistakes (this is to distinguish from condoning misconducts and violence). Tolerance and willing to forgive counterparts are nowhere to be seen nowadays, making professors, students, and everybody in the active society feel like they are walking on eggshells. It discourages speaking up for fear of being labelled and cancelled. This is only the beginning of group-think -- intellectual growth is at stake and that is only a small part of the grave consequences to be met. One can only say the demise of democracy is nearing if we continue to hold views as such. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the last two sections of the book, the authors asks "How did we get here?" Many things can be attributed to why the society is the way it is and these proposed factors range from depression and anxiety, political polarization, paranoid parenting, the decline of efficacy in meritocratic system, the decline of play in surge of technical advancements  and the obsessions over safetyism. The book ends with a set of solutions that the authors came up with to counter these discussed problems and how to foster a healthier generation to come, starting from the family, to school, and to community. Teaching young people that there is a thing called productive disagreement is a start. Portraying the progress of the world (Steven Pinker's Enlightenment Now) can relieve us of the pessimistic and depressing outlook of the future.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Original article The Coddling of the American Mind first appeared in The Atlantic: https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2015/09/the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/399356/</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>351</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-10-28 11:54:15</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-10-28 03:54:15</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-coddling-of-the-american-mind</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="books"><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1603857258]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[50416099977]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[362]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_oembed_72399cbc0348d8f8fc1e07c8660c16a3</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>4ao9NO2RcHqIZapL00ta0o8nas2zY5yWS48m</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/10/28/the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/4ao9no2rchqizapl00ta0o8nas2zy5yws48m/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 03:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/4ao9no2rchqizapl00ta0o8nas2zy5yws48m.pdf</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>361</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-10-28 11:53:11</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-10-28 03:53:11</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>4ao9no2rchqizapl00ta0o8nas2zy5yws48m</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>351</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/4ao9no2rchqizapl00ta0o8nas2zy5yws48m.pdf</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>de2515d2ad2c4a393fdc85fd62d3263b_XL</title>
  <link>https://eunicepark01.wordpress.com/2020/10/28/the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/de2515d2ad2c4a393fdc85fd62d3263b_xl/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 03:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>homeofwordsblog</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/de2515d2ad2c4a393fdc85fd62d3263b_xl.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>362</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-10-28 11:53:22</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-10-28 03:53:22</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>de2515d2ad2c4a393fdc85fd62d3263b_xl</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>351</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://eunicepark01.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/de2515d2ad2c4a393fdc85fd62d3263b_xl.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
